Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
A heat source?
What's thatk?
It's Sovereign Degwin.
Now we can achieve peace.
Sovereign Degwin!
What is it?
What was that light?
That's where the Revil Fleet's
main forces are located!
N-Not all of them are gone, but...
Not all of them are gone, but...
Space Fortress: A Baoa Qu
The Solar Ray has been fired at Gel Dorva!
Hey, you heard that, right?
Y-Yeah...
Hey, did you check the laser sensors?
Yeah. I heard, all right.
Did you hear at your station, too?
What's going on?
We're at level two battle stations.
Idle chatter is prohibited.
The Great Degwin's identification signal
was detected at the Gel Dorva line...
It seems odd.
The Great Degwin...?
Yes. And it was at the exact same point
that the enemy fleet was situated.
Were we notified about the Great Degwin
heading into battle?
No.
I see.
Maintain surveillance
on the enemy's remaining forces.
I doubt we wiped out even half of them.
Yes, ma'am.
The Great Degwin...
How strange.
Only the Saffron is left
from the 12th Division!
We have only 8 ships.
The Cisco's damaged too!
Some of them are damaged quite badly.
Fraw Bow!
Yes, sir!
Any word from the Luzal?
The main fleet has been ordered
to gather around the White Base.
So we're to stay put.
No. Have you heard anything else?
Nothing! They seem to be
in a state of chaos.
Attention White Base crew.
Everyone stand by at level 2 battle stations.
Can you figure anything out?
Yeah.
They used something like the Solar System.
The Solar System?
The Federation used it at Solomon.
Although this one's much more powerful.
White Base! Security code Beta Trois!
R-Roger!
My brave and loyal Zeon soldiers...
Half of the Federation fleet has been
reduced to stardust by our Solar Ray!
This brilliant light is proof
that the Zeon cause is just!
With the massive damage that
the Federation Forces have sustained...
...no matter how much fighting strength
they may have left...
...It Is of little consequence.
Dare I say it.
They are merely debris!
I declare it impossible...
...for this weak host of enemies
to force its way past A Baoa Qu.
Under the control of we, the chosen
superior race of Zeon, humanity can...
...at last ensure its eternal survival!
If this war drags on...
...it will pose a threat to humanity itself.
We must teach the incompetents
of the Earth Federation a lesson!
Now is the time for humanity...
...to stand and face
the future that awaits us!
Sieg Zeon!
Sieg...
Second and third battalions
will advance from N Point.
We will gather all remaining ships,
with the Luzal as our flagship...
...and proceed from S Point.
We obviously lack fighting strength.
If only we could use our Solar System too.
But I think we'll be okay.
It's true that A Baoa Qu's firepower
is greatest where we want to attack...
...but it's also their weakest point.
The operation will succeed.
Is that Newtype intuition?
Yes.
Ready to synchronize timers.
3... 2... 1... 0! Operation starting now!
Right!
All hands go to level 1 battle stations.
We'll break through the F-line in 10 minutes!
Fraw Bow.
Don't give up hope, no matter what happens.
We shouldn't waste our lives over this.
Thanks, Amuro.
I promise I'll never give up.
That's the Fraw Bow I know.
Well, see you later.
Amuro, don't do anything crazy.
Okay!
Be right there!
Sure.
We're heading back to E-Block!
Good luck, everybody!
Where's Hayato?
He's stuck on Fraw Bow!
Well, good for him!
What a creepy laugh.
He's not hurting anyone.
I know that, but...
Good luck!
We believe in you!
Thanks!
Amuro...
What you said back there... Is it true?
I lied.
If Newtypes could predict the future,
then we all wouldn't have to suffer.
If Amuro hadn't said what he did,
the crew would've abandoned ship.
From fear, I mean.
Well, of course.
Humans can't become gods
even if they try with all their might.
The enemy's creating a
beam interference field...
Respond with missiles.
Don't move our mobile suits yet.
The carrier Dolos is on schedule.
Hold off for now...
Reroute half the vessels in S Field
over to N Field.
Damned Federation.
Not bad for having lost their main forces.
Gwazine entering E Field.
It's likely Rear Admiral Kycilia's vessel.
Right. Reroute it now to N Field.
Yes, sir!
That's strange...
The doesn't match the number of ships
that Kycilia set out with.
Every one of the new Gelgoog types
has been dispatched.
There's nothing left for me to pilot, is there?
Want to try out the Zeong?
I understand it's only
80 percent complete, though.
Zeong...?
A mobile suit that partially...
...incorporates the psycommu system
developed for the Elmeth.
You should be able to handle it.
Then it has the Braw Bro's characteristics?
Yes.
I doubt anyone has launched in the Zeong.
Give it a try.
In the meantime, I'll go see Gihren.
Right...
80 percent, huh...
Magellan-class destroyed, sir.
The enemy mobile suit forces have launched.
Alright, Dolos. Don't fail me now.
Lady Kycilia has returned.
You're late.
I apologize profusely.
I heard that the Elmeth was destroyed.
Yes.
So it couldn't even handle a single Gundam.
We'll use the Zeong.
That incomplete model?
We can't defeat the Gundam unless
we use somebody...
...who might be a Newtype.
Char... once again.
Dolos is advancing!
You're obsessed.
The Great Degwin. Where is it deployed?
Is it at Zum City?
It was destroyed.
It moved out too far ahead.
Really? Did Sovereign Degwin
lend you his ship?
Don't be irritating.
Kycilia. Do you think our father
would hand over the Great Degwin?
I don't think so.
Then there's your answer.
Our forces are simply overwhelming.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
80 percent complete?
You've got to be kidding!
In its current state,
the Zeong can fight at 100 percent!
But it has no legs.
Legs are just for show!
The brass doesn't understand things like that!
You explained how to operate it.
But the psycommu...
Do you think I can handle that?
Your Newtype abilities
are unknown, Captain.
So I can't guarantee anything.
You're very frank. I don't appreciate it.
Sorry.
If it makes you feel any better, Captain,
I'm sure you'll do well!
Thanks. I believe you.
It looks like your numbers are
too small to attack us here.
The Dolos is holding its ground quite well.
Send all N Field fleets forward and...
A new fleet? A Federation Forces one?!
What's that?!
Are you certain?
It's in the N Field line.
We're gathering data now.
The Federation's fighting well.
Think so?
It's merely the last futile effort of
their surviving forces.
Maybe so...
What's the status of Captain Char's Zeong?
What is it?
How's the Zeong?
It's good to go.
Well then... A new enemy fleet
was discovered in S Field.
Go after them with
the 34th Mobile Suit Corps!
Yes, Ma'am! We'll take out
all the enemy entering S Field!
The Federation won't have
any more forces in reserve.
We should be able to defend S Field
with our current strength, eh?
Yes.
A man who killed his own father...!
Now. The question is...
...whether or not I actually have
definite Newtype potential.
Die!
Elevate 2 degrees! Retreat!
Yes, sir!
Good!
But... Where is he?
Over there! A mobile suit team.
It's him!
This guy's strong! Is it Char?!
He's behind me?! What the...!
A Newtype who's stronger than Char! But...!
But landing on A Baoa Qu
is more important now!
My true enemy is within there.
And it's not Char!
It looks like the Dolos forces
will take care of N Field.
Isn't that nice?
Father was aboard the Great Degwin...
Yet you destroyed it along
with the Federation Forces. Why?
I had no choice.
Nothing would have resulted from
an ill-timed peace initiative.
But there was no need to let him die...
"Supreme Commander".
Enough of the jokes.
How surprisingly naive, my dear brother.
Isn't that Supreme Commander Gihren?
Get rid of the body now!
Even a supreme commander
can't get away with patricide!
If any of you disagree, you can
file charges after the battle!
Supreme Commander Gihren
died honorably in battle!
The Dolos fleet has been defeated!
Lady Kycilia, your orders...
Yes, Twanning. I appreciate it.
I'll take over command of A Baoa Qu!
Dispatch mobile suit forces to N Field!
What's the status of S Field?!
We've eliminated
10 of the enemy's 25 vessels.
But the other vessels are
hanging on in S Field.
Send Char's Zeong to the front line!
Concentrate mobile suit forces in S Field!
Go...!!
You're mine...!
Who's next?
Those new models are quite something!
Fraw Bow.
Tell Sayla to keep her G-Fighter
near the White Base.
Yes, sir!
Mirai! The enemy's defense seemed
to weaken momentarily just then.
Yes. That was rather strange.
We may be struggling,
but from the looks of it, so are they.
So it seems.
Amuro!
It's pathetic. I've lost sight of the Gundam.
Where is he?!
They're good.
The enemy mobile suits
have landed in N Field.
Hm. That's a concern.
How's S Field holding up?
It looks like the Gundam
has broken through.
And Char's Zeong?
Obstructed by the enemy,
and can't get close to the Gundam.
It's his first time in the Zeong, after all.
I made it!
It's Char! I think he found me!
I can see him! I can see my enemy!
But the Gelgoogs and Doms aren't
doing well. Why is that, Twanning?
Ma'am! It appears that many
of the pilots are student recruits.
Students?
Yes. But I assure you,
they've been fully trained.
I believe you...
But it's the outcome I'm concerned about.
It seems they're just too weak.
I'm terribly sorry, Ma'am.
But their patriotic spirit is...
If only the Supreme Commander had
taken notice of Newtypes earlier...
Draw the enemy into A Baoa Qu
so we can pick them off!
There aren't too many of the enemy left!
I've gotta do it!
Why did you have to show up here?!
N-No...!
Mother...!
From the other direction?!
Char!
He dodged me?!
Not again...!
Char was beginning to feel intense alarm.
The Zeong had been
developed for Newtypes...
...and he was frustrated by his inability
to draw out its full power.
The Gundam pilot was unquestionably
driving him into a corner.
But surely I must be a Newtype too...!
The finale is at hand.
Amuro and Char duel without mobile suits.
This is no longer a war.
It must be the fate imposed on Newtypes.
Meanwhile, the red flames of A Baoa Qu
engulf the White Base.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Escape.
Next Time
Escape
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...